Black Is King is a music film directed by Beyoncé.
This visual album from Beyoncé reimagines the lessons of "The Lion King" (2019)
for today's young kings and queens in search of their own crowns.
Black Is King is a 2020 American musical film co-written,
executive produced, and directed by Beyoncé.
It is a visual companion to the 2019 album The Lion King: The Gift,
curated by Beyoncé for the film The Lion King (2019).
The film tells the story of a young African prince (Folajomi Akinmurele)
who is exiled from his kingdom after his father's death.
As he grows into a man (Nyaniso Dzedze), he undergoes a journey of self-identity, using the guidance of his ancestor
(Beyoncé), childhood love (Nandi Madida), and his own subconscious (Stephen Ojo) to reclaim his throne.
The prince's journey acts as an allegory for the African diaspora's journey of discovering, reclaiming and celebrating their culture
and heritage, which is echoed by the inclusion of spoken-word poetry that focuses on the question of black identity.
Black Is King was in production for over a year,
across six countries on three continents.
Beyoncé wanted to recruit a diverse cast and crew and to
provide opportunities for new talent.
The music, dances, costumes, hairstyles, and sets were designed to showcase the beauty
and richness of the cultures in the African continent and diaspora.
The film was released globally on Disney+ on July 31, 2020, and was aired the following day across
Sub-Saharan Africa on M-Net and Canal+ Afrique and across the Middle East and North Africa on OSN.
An extended version of "Black Parade" was used for the film's credits, and was
included in a deluxe edition of The Gift released alongside the film.
The film received praise for Beyoncé's direction, the cinematography,
score, costume design, subject matter, and cultural themes.
It received six nominations at the 63rd Annual Grammy
Awards, including Best Music Film.
"Brown Skin Girl" won the award for Best Music Video, while "Black
Parade" won the award for Best R&B Performance.
It was Beyoncé's 28th Grammy win, making her the most awarded
singer and female artist in Grammy history.
The film also won the Primetime Emmy Award for Outstanding Costumes for a Variety,
Nonfiction, or Reality Program at the 73rd Primetime Emmy Awards.